The demon barber of Fleet Street.
Sweeney Todd is a drama, horror, thriller film directed by David Moore.
A BBC adaptation of the Victorian "penny dreadful" tale of 19th century "demon barber" Sweeney Todd,
of Fleet Street, who cuts the throats of unsuspecting clients in his London shop.
Sweeney Todd, played by Ray Winstone.
Mrs Lovett, played by Essie Davis.
Fielding, played by David Warner.
Matthew, played by Tom Hardy.
Sweeney's Father, played by David Bradley.
Gaoler, played by Anthony O'Donnell.
Sweeney Todd is a fictional character who first appeared as the villain of
the penny dreadful serial The String of Pearls (1846–1847).
The original tale became a feature of 19th-century melodrama and London legend.
A barber from Fleet Street, Todd murders his customers with a
straight razor and gives their corpses to Mrs.
Lovett, his partner in crime, who bakes their flesh into meat pies.
The tale has been retold many times since in various media.
Claims that Sweeney Todd was a historical person are disputed strongly by
scholars, although possible legendary prototypes exist.
The tone is dark and emotional and intense.